Guide to the Ira and Edita Morirs Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series VIII: Documents
  - Estate Papers of Ira V. Morris, 3 May 1972 (Box 44, Folder 719)
  - Last Will and Testament for Edita Morris, 1973 (Box 44, Folder 720)
  - Last Will and Testament for Edwin Seaver, 1974 (Box 44, Folder 721)
  - Certificate of Cremation of Elaine K. Seaver, 23 July 1974 (Box 44, Folder 722)
  - Death Certificate for Elaine Seaver, 24 July 1974 (Box 44, Folder 723)
  - Birth Certificate of [Edwin] Soloman, copy, 7 May 1975 (Box 44, Folder 724)
  - Census Record for Edward Soloman, 5 June 1975 (Box 44, Folder 725)
  - Lease Extension Agreement between Beekman Town House, Inc. and Edwin Seaver, 15 July 1980 (Box 44, Folder 726)
  - Death Certificate for Edita Morris, text in French, copy, 18 March 1988 (Box 44, Folder 727)
- Series IX: Photographs
  Mostly black and white photographs along with a few negatives and color prints. The identified pictures depict the Morris family and friends, the Hiroshima Rest House, atomic bombing of Japan, and related subjects. Many of the pictures are unidentified.
  - Albert Schweitzer Prize Reception, 21 Nov. 1961 (Box 44, Folder 728)
  - Animals, 1943-1945, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 729)
  - Artwork, 1952, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 730)
  - Artwork, n.d. (Box 680)
  - Atomic Bomb Victims, 1958, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 731)
  - Exhibits, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 732)
  - The Flowers of Hiroshima, opera, 1967, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 733)
  - Hiroshima Atomic Bomb Dome, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 734)
  - Hiroshima Bombing, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 735)
  - Hiroshima Bombing, n.d. (Box 680)
  - Hiroshima Bombing, n.d. (Box 680)
  - Hiroshima Bombing, n.d. (Box 680)
  - Hiroshima Festival, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 736)
  - Hiroshima Memorial Cenotaph, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 737)
  - Hiroshima Rest House, 1958-1969, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 738)
  - Identified People, 1893-1984, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 739)
  - Identified People, n.d. (Box 680)
  - Identified People, n.d. (Box 680)
  - Identified Places, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 740)
  - Morris, Edita, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 741)
  - Morris, Ira V., 1944, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 742)
  - Morris, Ira V. and Edita, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 743)
  - Morris, Ira V. and Edita: Norway-Sweden Trip, 1964 (Box 46, Folder 744)
  - Ogawa, Ayako, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 745)
  - Seaver, Edwina, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 746)
  - Unidentified People, n.d. (Box 680)
  - Unidentified People, 1899-1984 (Box 46, Folder 747)
  - Unidentified People: Asia, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 748)
  - Unidentified Places, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 749)
  - Unidentified Places, n.d. (Box 680)
  - Unidentified Portraits: Female, 1939, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 750)
  - Unidentified Portraits: Female, n.d. (Box 680)
  - Unidentified Portraits: Groups, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 751)
  - Unidentified Portraits: Groups, n.d. (Box 680)
  - Unidentified Portraits: Groups, n.d. (Box 680)
  - Unidentified Portraits: Male, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 752)
  - Unidentified Portraits: Male, n.d. (Box 680)
  - Negatives, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 753)
  - Hiroshima Rest House: Glass Plate Negatives, n.d. (Box 48)
- Series X: Art
  Two pencil drawings on paper, arranged alphabetically by the observed subject of each piece.
  - Pencil drawing of crucified figure, n.d., (27.8 x 21.4 cm ) (Box 47, Folder 754)
  - Pencil drawing of two seated figures, n.d., (19 x 14.3 cm ) (Box 47, Folder 755)
- Series XI: Books
  Mainly bound books written by Ira V. and Edita Morris. There are numerous foreign editions of their novels, especially The Flowers of Hiroshima. In addition, there are books written by other authors, five with inscriptions written to the Morris’s. Arranged alphabetically by author, then title.
  - Aschberg, Olof Gryningen till en ny tid (text in Swedish), Stockholm, 1961 (Box 47)
    [Inscription to Edita and Ira Morris, 19 Dec. 1961]
  - Ferlin, Nils Dikter: i folkupplaga (text in Swedish), Stockholm, 1954 (Box 47)
    [Inscription to Edita and Ira Morris, 21 Dec. 1961]
  - Gunnarsson, Gunnar Salige er de Enfoldige (text in Danish), Denmark, 1920 (Box 47)
  - Hiroshima-shi (Japan) Horishima shinshi, v.1 (text in Japanese), 1981 (Box 47)
  - Morris, Constance Lily Marie-Thérèse: Le Dernier Conservateur (text in French), Paris, 1937 (Box 47)
  - Morris, Edita Charade, London, 1949 (Box 47)
  - Morris, Edita Echo in Asia: A Fictional Travelogue, London, 1961 (Box 47)
  - Morris, Edita Echo in Asia: A Fictional Travelogue (German edition), Munich, 1962 (Box 47)
  - Morris, Edita The Flowers and the Seeds of Hiroshima (German edition), Munich, 1967 (Box 49)
  - Morris, Edita The Flowers of Hiroshima, London, 1961 (Box 49)
  - Morris, Edita The Flowers of Hiroshima (Bulgarian edition), London, 1964 (Box 49)
  - Morris, Edita The Flowers of Hiroshima (Czech edition), 1963 (Box 49)
  - Morris, Edita The Flowers of Hiroshima (Finnish edition), 1965 (Box 49)
  - Morris, Edita The Flowers of Hiroshima (French edition), Paris, 1961 (Box 49)
  - Morris, Edita The Flowers of Hiroshima (French edition), Paris, 1961 (Box 49)
  - Morris, Edita The Flowers of Hiroshima (German edition), 1960 (Box 49)
  - Morris, Edita The Flowers of Hiroshima (German edition), 1963 (Box 49)
  - Morris, Edita The Flowers of Hiroshima (German edition), 1963 (Box 49)
  - Morris, Edita The Flowers of Hiroshima (German edition), Berlin, 1965 (Box 49)
  - Morris, Edita The Flowers of Hiroshima (Greek edition), 1963 (Box 49)
  - Morris, Edita The Flowers of Hiroshima (Hindi edition), 1965 (Box 49)
  - Morris, Edita The Flowers of Hiroshima (Hungarian edition), Budapest, 1963 (Box 49)
  - Morris, Edita The Flowers of Hiroshima (Japanese edition), Tokyo (Box 49)
  - Morris, Edita The Flowers of Hiroshima (Norwegian edition), Oslo, 1962 (Box 49)
  - Morris, Edita The Flowers of Hiroshima (Sinhalese edition), 1963 (Box 49)
  - Morris, Edita The Flowers of Hiroshima (Sinhalese edition), 1963 (Box 49)
  - Morris, Edita The Flowers of Hiroshima (Slovenian edition), 1966 (Box 49)
  - Morris, Edita The Flowers of Hiroshima (Slovenian edition), 1966 (Box 49)
  - Morris, Edita The Flowers of Hiroshima (Spanish edition), Barcelona, 1962 (Box 49)
  - Morris, Edita A Happy Day (Swedish edition), 1974 (Box 49)
  - Morris, Edita How Keeping, Hope Fine (Swedish edition), 1977 (Box 49)
  - Morris, Edita Karriär (text in Swedish), Stockholm, 1940 (Box 50)
  - Morris, Edita Love to Vietnam, London, 1969 (Box 50)
  - Morris, Edita Love to Vietnam (Dutch edition), 1968 (Box 50)
  - Morris, Edita Love to Vietnam (Dutch edition), 1968 (Box 50)
  - Morris, Edita Love to Vietnam (German edition), Munich, 1967 (Box 50)
  - Morris, Edita Love to Vietnam (Polish edition), Krakow, 1972 (Box 50)
  - Morris, Edita Love to Vietnam (Turkish edition), 1970 (Box 50)
  - Morris, Edita Love to Vietnam (Turkish edition), 1970 (Box 50)
  - Morris, Edita Love to Vietnam (Turkish edition), 1970 (Box 50)
  - Morris, Edita Melodie der Liebe (text in German), Munich, 1957 (Box 50)
  - Morris, Edita My Darling from the Lions (German edition), Munich, 1945 (Box 50)
  - Morris, Edita My Darling from the Lions (German edition), Munich, 1945 (Box 50)
  - Morris, Edita The Seeds of Hiroshima, Berlin, 1966 (Box 50)
  - Morris, Edita The Seeds of Hiroshima (Dutch edition), 1965 (Box 50)
  - Morris, Edita The Seeds of Hiroshima (Finnish edition), Helsinki, 1965 (Box 50)
  - Morris, Edita The Seeds of Hiroshima (French edition), Paris, 1965 (Box 50)
  - Morris, Edita The Seeds of Hiroshima (French edition), Paris, 1965 (Box 51)
  - Morris, Edita The Seeds of Hiroshima (German edition), Berlin, [1965] (Box 51)
  - Morris, Edita The Seeds of Hiroshima (German edition), Munich, 1965 (Box 51)
  - Morris, Edita The Seeds of Hiroshima (Polish edition), Krakow, 1967 (Box 51)
  - Morris, Edita The Solo Dancer (Dutch edition), 1971 (Box 51)
  - Morris, Ira Nelson Heritage from My Father: An Autobiography, New York, 1947 (Box 51)
  - Morris, Ira V. The Bombay Meeting, Garden City, NY, 1955 (Box 51)
  - Morris, Ira V. The Bombay Meeting (French edition), 1957 (Box 51)
  - Morris, Ira V. Liberty Street, New York and London, 1944 (Box 51)
  - Morris, Ira V. Marching Orders (French edition), Paris, 1947 (Box 51)
  - Morris, Ira V. Marching Orders (French edition), Paris, 1947 (Box 51)
  - Morris, Ira V. The Paper Wall (French edition), Paris, 1959 (Box 51)
  - Söderbergh, Bengt Stigbygeln (text in Swedish), Stockholm, 1961 (Box 51)
    [Inscription to Edita and Ira Morris, Aug. 1962]
  - Strindberg, August Dödsdansen (text in Swedish), Stockholm, 1921 (Box 52)
  - Strindberg, August Näktergalen I Wittenberg Kristina Gustav III, Stockholm, 1924 (Box 52)
  - Takman, John Vår vid sydkinesiska sjön, Stockholm, 1959 (Box 52)
    [Inscription to Edita Morris, n.d.]
  - Skall Sverige Ha Atombombe?, Stockholm, 1958 (Box 52)
    [Inscription to Edita and Ira Morris, n.d.]
  - Series XII: Printed Materials
    Principally newspaper clippings about Ira V. and Edita Morris's writing careers. Also contains business cards, an obituary for Ira’s mother Constance Lily Morris, and miscellaneous materials. Arranged alphabetically by title.
    - Blank Postcards, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 756)
    - Business Cards, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 757)
    - Obituary: Morris, Constance Lily, 15 May 1954 (Box 52, Folder 758)
    - Pamphlet for film "The Young One", [1961] (Box 52, Folder 759)
    - Press Clippings: Miscellaneous, 1930-1975, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 760)
    - Press Clippings: Morris, Edita, 1943-1976, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 761)
    - Press Clippings: Morris, Ira, 1957-1972 (Box 52, Folder 762)
    - Press Clippings: Morris, Ira and Edita, 1961-1963, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 763)
    - Program for Recital by Mary Louise Brown, pianist, 20 Feb. 1958 (Box 52, Folder 764)
    - Reader's Digest, 1936 & 1943 (Box 52, Folder 765)
    - The Star Light Messenger, 1963-1964 (Box 52, Folder 766)
    - Town & Country, 1943 (Box 52, Folder 767)